Guide to the Samuel Roth papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Writings, 1907-1990s
  - I.2. Subseries: Writings by Adelaide Roth, 1970s-1990s
    - I.2.1. Sub-subseries: Research Materials, 1950s-1990s (Box 22)
      - "Letters from Lewisberg," Undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - "Letters from Prison," Undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - "Libraries," 1990s (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - "Library," Undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - "Library Catalogue," Undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - List of Roth Books, Undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Milton Hindus, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - "Misc.--& Source Material," Undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Notes
        - General, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 14 to 15)
        - Plain Brown Wrapper, Undated, (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Wroth Wrackt Joyce, Undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Notebooks
        - General, 1980s, Undated (5 of 6 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 5 to 9)
        - General, 1980s, Undated (1 of 6 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - "Copy Editions," Undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - French, Undated (mostly blank) (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - "Translation Art Memoirs SR Library," 1969 (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - With Contents Lists, Undated, (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 5 to 7)
        - With Floppy Disks, 1970s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - "Obscenity-Porn," Undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - "People," Undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Plagiarism, Undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Quotes by Famous Authors, Undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - "Talese," 1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Ulysses, Undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - "University of Texas," 1990s (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - I.3. Subseries: Writings by Others, 1907-1986
    The bulk of the material in this sub-series includes typescripts of novels or short stories that never made it to publication in any of Roth's many imprints. Some of documents are alternate versions of published works. Many of the longer works were originally bound by Roth in soft binders marked “Property of Samuel Roth.” Among the works never published are pieces by Maxwell Bodenheim, Ludwig Marcuse, Claude McKay, Harry Roskolenko, Arthur Symons, Denys Val Baker, George Sylvester Viereck among others. The authors of some of the materials in this sub-series are unidentified or have used pseudonyms.
    - Absolute, John-- The Life and Times of Diddywot, the Wicked Youth, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Anonymous, "Alas, Poor Bollington!," Undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Antrim, Robert--"Sam Roth: Prometheus of the Unprintable," 1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Bodenheim, Maxwell
      - The Borderlands of Passion: A Novel of Greenwich Village, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Clara: A Novel--Incomplete Copies, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Boylesve, René-- Les Bains de Bade, With Keene Wallis' Enlish Translation, Undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Colum, Mary and Padraic-- Our Friend James Joyce, 1958 (Note by Roth) (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Coppard, A.E.--"The Man From Kilsheelan," Undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Crowley, Aleister-- White Stains, Undated (Annotations by Roth) (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Eddie-- Over Sexty, 1950s (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - de Caylus, Comte Philippe--"Rococo in the Raw: Old Paris from a Coachman's Seat," Undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Deutsch, Ursula--Poems, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Donnelly, RB-- Just Like the Flowers, Dear!, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Douglas, Lord Alfred--"A Sonnet," from The Cherwell, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Droz, Gustave-- Papa, Mamma and Baby, 1930 (notations by Roth) (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Dr Enlind, Arvid--Preface to Inside Hitler, 1941 (with letter and card) (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Erskine, John-- The Shadowed Hour, Published by The Lyric, 1917 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Fletcher, Frances-- A Boat of Glass--Signed "For David Zorn," 1926 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Franklin, Benjamin--"On Body Odors," Undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Gertzman, Jay--"Mail-Order Distribution of Erotica in the 1930s," Undated (with note to Adelaide Roth) (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Gilman, Sander--"The Ashes of the Holocaust," 1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Golden, Lon [pseudonym]
      - The Things They Love--From "Where They Dare Not Tread," Undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - The Things They Love, Undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Hamalian, Leo--"Nobody Knows My Names," 1974 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Hamill, John--"Confession"--Copy Re: Hoover exposé, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Heine, Heinrich-- Poems & Ballads, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Hemingway, Ernest-- Collected Poems, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Hill, Oliver-- Pan's Garden, 1928 (with draft by Roth of "The Bachelor as a Child Lover") (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Hindus, Milton--Excerpt From The Crippled Giant, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Hirsch, Tina-- The House Next Door--Screenplay Based on a Book by Elizabeth Fenwick, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Jogge, John
      - Murder in the Nth Degree, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 5 to 8)
    - Journal of Modern Literature, April, 1974 (with annotations) (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Kugel, Candice--Poem About Roth, Undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Lorrain, Jean--"Princesses of Ivory and of Ecstasy," Undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Lorenz, Marie--"A Self-Made Woman," Undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - The Lyric --Various Poems, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Marcuse, Ludwig--"Nietzsche's Biographer," 1950s (with letters by Roth) (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - McKay, Claude-- Amiable With Big Teeth, 1941, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Menard, Wilmon--Introduction to Vahine!, 1968 (with clippings) (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - m'ira-- Friends & Strangers--Introduction by Norman Lockridge, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Morgan, Meilys--"Love in the Mountains," Undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Morton, Thomas J.
      - "His Follow-Home Woman," Undated (with letter) (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - "Timothy Jerimiah O'Malley," Undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Page, Francis-- Confucius Comes to Broadway, 1940 (with annotations by Roth) (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - "Poets Corner," Undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Reboux, Paul-- The ABC of Love: A Dictionary--With Page by Keene Wallis, Undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Reznard, Jules-- Portrait of a Middle-Aged Poet, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Robinson, Edwin Arlington-- Lancelot: A Poem--Published by The Lyric, 1920 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Roth, Joseph--"DIZ," "Hoochypap," and "Smith," 1952-1960 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Roth, Richard--Writings, 1960s (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Ryan, Bill and Leslie Horwitz, "The Man Who Paved the Way"-- from HUSTLER, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Roskolenko, Harry
      - Four Titled Chapters of Unidentified Manuscript, Undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Untitled Novel, Undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Saintsbury, George-- Essays on French Novelists--With Letter, 1910 (autographed) (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Sawyer, Joseph H.
      - "Still Water Runs Deep," Undated (annotations by Roth) (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - "White-Collar Crime," Undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Score, John B-- Natural Immunity & Good Health--With Letter, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Shields, Jane and Val Baker--"MS and Returns," Undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Symons, Arthur
      - The Life, Thoughts, & Adventures of Arthur Symons--With Preface by Samuel Roth, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - "Four Unpublished Plays by Arthur Symons," 1907 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Tobie--French Play--With Incomplete Translation, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Trumbo, Dalton--Two-Page Text Re: Peggy Roth, Undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Val Baker, Denys-- Three in One Bed, Undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Viereck, George Sylvester
      - "Doubtful Poems," Undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - "Eyeless Paradise," aka "Are Women Necessary?" Undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - "Roses of Priapus," Undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - "Preliminary Suggestions" for Samuel Roth's Count Me Among the Missing, Undated (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Wallace, Dixie--"For the Love of Dad," Undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Wallis, Keene
      - Dante's Paradise in Translation, Undated (incomplete) (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - Paradise by Dante Alighieri, Undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Poems, Undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Weldon, John Lee-- The Male Rosary (A Play in One Act), Undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Willard, Otto-- Vahine! Vahine! A Sex Survey of Tahitian Trollops, 1960s (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Woods, Andrew H--"Syphilis in Shakespeare…", 1934 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Wyckoff, James--"The Door Between," Undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Series II: Legal Documents 1926-1969
  The files in this series that Roth compiled himself were kept intact and their original titles preserved. A large amount of legal correspondence—spanning decades—is here, as well as official court documents.
  - II.1. Subseries: Notes and Prepared Legal Files, 1931-1959
    This sub-series contains legal files and notes that Samuel Roth prepared and arranged himself. The original folder titles were kept; if the folder was untitled, then the name it now bears reflects the dates of the documents it contains. Most of the material consists of court-issued documents, photocopies, transcripts, and even correspondence. The bulk of the legal files are contained within this sub-series. The order in which the material was kept within Roth's original folders has been maintained.
    - "1949-1952"
      - April Term, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Court Proceedings, Undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - "Sexual Conduct of Men and Women," 1949 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "1954-1955"
      - "Dear Sir," re: Avalon Press, Undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - & L. Docket 17/287, Undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - & L. Docket 19/93 Undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Good Times Mailability, by Scheiman, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - H.E. Docket No.2/341, by Atlas, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Juvenile Delinquency Testimony, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - "Atlas Dealings," 1950s (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - "Book injunction lifted," 1931 (Hoover book) (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "The Case, Preparatory to 1955 Trial," 1955-1958 (with Parole application) (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "Cases (parts of) 1929-59," 1920s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 19 to 20)
    - "H.E. Docket No. 2/245," 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "How would this serve as a windup to the brief?" Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "Notes on the case," Undated (Includes "Table of Contents") (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Post-Office," 1938-1950 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Roth v. Post-Office," 1956 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "(Roth) GOOD TIMES v. POST OFFICE DEPT," 1954 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "ROTH--GOOD TIMES v SHEEHAN," 1954-1956 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Samuel Roth etc v Riegelman-USDCSNY 85-340," 1948-1957 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "Supreme Court," 1958 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "The 26 Counts and the Issue They Raise," 1956 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Untitled by Roth
      - Regarding Court of Appeals, 1960s (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Bridgehead Books, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - C148-9 Forms, Photocopies, Notes, 1957-1960 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Court forms, Correspondence, Photocopies, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Exhibits, Registers, Court Forms, 1956-1959 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - General Release Form, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Mail Order Forms, 1950s (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Motion for a New Trial and Other Forms, 1957-1959 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Notes, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Roth v. Goldman, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Sworn Statement, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - II.2. Subseries: Legal correspondence, 1926-1969
    Contained here is correspondence related to various court cases in which Samuel Roth was involved. As with the other series, folders previously compiled and labeled by Roth were kept intact, and whenever possible, the same folder title was used. Included here is in-coming and out-going correspondence of Samuel Roth, and his spouse, Pauline Roth, related to Roth’s various court cases.
    - General
      - 1954-1961 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Post Office Visit, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Albrecht, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Alter, William and Maury Maverick, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Atlas, Nicholas, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Atlas to Kinsey, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Bosone, Beck, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - De Witt & Van Aken, 1926, 1928 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Fleshin, J.B., 1964-1966 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Monte Levy, Herbert, 1956-1959 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Oberwager, 1934 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - O'Brien, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Olitt, J. Jerome, 1966-1969 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Rabinowitz & Boudin, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Sayler, Probation Officer, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Scheiman, 1956-1957 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Strachan, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Terrizzi, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Wittenberg, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - II.3. Subseries: Court Documents, 1947-1961
    Documents issued by courts and lawyers during Roth's many trials: briefs, pamphlets, minutes, statements, are found here. The Briefs, from the Post Office Department, the Supreme Court of the United States, the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, and the United States District Court Southern District of New York, cover many different specific sections of Roth's trials and related legal matters. Included here are both bound briefs printed by the court press (italicized titles) and typewritten drafts issued by the defendant's lawyers or those representing the court.
    - Briefs
      - Deposition Regarding Whittaker Chambers, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - Hearings on Scope of Soviet Activity in US, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - Post Office Department, 1954-1957 (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Supreme Court New York County, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Supreme Court of the United States
        - No. 582, Petition for Writ of Certoriari, Undated (Box 33, Folder 27)
        - October Term, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 28)
        - October Term, 1956 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 29)
        - October Term, 1956 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - October Term, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - October Term, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - October Term, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - October Term, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit
        - Appendix to Appellant's Brief, Undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Brief and Appendix for Appellant, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Brief for the USA, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Brief of Appellant, Undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
        - No. 387, October Term, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - Notice of Motion for Bail, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        - Reply Brief of Appellant, Undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
        - Roth v. Goldman, No. 152, October Term, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 13)
        - RULES, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 14)
        - Transcript of Record, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - United States District Court Southern District of New York
        - Affidavits I-VI, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - Affidavit and Rebuttal, 1959-1961 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - "Discarded" Motions and Drafts, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 3)
        - "Judge Cashin's Denial," Memorandum, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Notice of a Motion for a New Trial, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        - Notices of Settlement, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - Stipulations of Discontinuance, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 7)
        - Summons, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Mandatory Release and Parole, 1960-1961 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Roth v. United States-- Stenographer's Minutes, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Roth v. United States--Summary by Monte Levy, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Series III: Correspondence 1909-1993
  The material in this series spans Samuel Roth’s lifetime and includes both personal and professional correspondence. Adelaide Roth’s correspondence, both personal and research-related, is also here.
  - III.1. Subseries: Samuel Roth, 1909-1971
    This sub-series consists of Samuel Roth's correspondence, both personal and professional and includes “prison letters” that Roth wrote while serving time. The bulk of these letters were addressed to his wife, Pauline. Also here is a large amount of professional and business correspondence. The folder titles used by Roth's own filing system have been kept and are indicated by quotation marks. Roth’s chronological arrangement of this material has been maintained.
    Roth's early correspondence (1915-1925), while wide, is not deep. Here also is found general correspondence regarding Roth's short-lived journal, The Lyric, and the Poetry Bookshop, Two Worlds, and other publishing-related correspondence. When the material was originally kept in an originally-labeled folder, the same folder title was used for the finding aid.
    - General
      - 1917-1925, 1950-1973, Undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - 1931-1939 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - 1940s (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - "1909-16," 1916-1918 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - "1917," 1916-1919 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - "1918-19," 1918-1919 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "1920-21," 1920-1925 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - "1922-25," 1922-1926 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Alma, C.B., 1921-1922 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Anonymous, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Beach, Sylvia, 1925 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Beau, 1926 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Bennett, James, Director of Prisons, 1956, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1917-1919 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Bryher, 1921 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Buck, Thomas F, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - The Colonial Press, 1949-1966 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Congregation Shearith Israel, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - "Copyright Matters," 1930-1968 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Copyright Office, Library of Congress, 1963-1968 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - "The Death of Dr. Bell," 1931-1932 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, Lord Alfred, 1932-1933 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Eban, Abba, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Eliot, T.S., 1921, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Elliott, John Tiffany, 1953-1958 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Embry, Jacqueline, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Erskine, John, 1917-1920 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Fletcher, Frances, 1925, Undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Fletcher, John Gould, 1917 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1922 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - A Golden Treasury of the World's Wit and Wisdom, 1936, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Hartman, Gustave, 1964-1967 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - H.D. (Hilda Aldington), 1918-1919 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Housand, Charles E--Fellow Inmate, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Jennings, Leslie N., 1917-1918 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Kiki-- The Education of a French Model, 1950-1957, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Kin, David George, 1949-1953 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Kugel, James L., 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Kugel, John Hans, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Lowell, Amy, 1917-1919 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - The Man Who Killed Kitchener, 1932-1933 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - McKay, Claude, 1941 (Includes Contract) (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - My Sister and I, 1952-1958, Undated (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Oppenheim, James, 1916-1917 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Plotkin, David G., 1941-1942 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Post, Samuel H., Award Books, 1965-1966 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1921, 1925 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Prison Letters
      - Roth, Adelaide Kugel, 1956-1960 (Box 36, Folder 32)
      - Roth Family, 1928-1930 (Box 36, Folder 33)
      - Roth, Joseph, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Roth, Pauline, 1936-1939 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Roth, Pauline Roth, 1956-1960, (4 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Roth, Peggy, 1958, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Reiser, Oliver P., 1945-1946 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Roth, Adelaide, 1960s, Undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Roth, Joseph, 1909-1919 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Roth, Pauline, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Roth, Robert, 1942, Undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Ryan, William, 1973-1975 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Samuel, Maurice, 1915-1919 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Seven Sirens Press and Other Imprints, 1950s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Symons, Arthur, 1921-1926 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Tannenbaum, Frank, 1916-1917, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Teasdale Filsinger, Sara, 1917-1919 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1917, 1921 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Vogel, Jesse--Regarding The Education of a French Model, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Waggish Tales, 1933, 1943, Undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw, 1922 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Whol, M., 1963 (found in copy of Jews Must Live (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Wood, Clement, 1921-1922 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Woodberry, George Edward, 1917-1918 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Zangwill, Israel, 1920-1925 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - III.2. Subseries: Adelaide Kugel Roth, 1974-1993
    Included here are Adelaide Roth’s many communications with various archives and libraries regarding Samuel Roth. The letters often include photocopies, clippings, and notes. Most of the material here was arranged by Adelaide Roth herself and every effort was made to maintain her arrangement.
    - General, 1974-1984 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - "FBI - FOIA," 1981 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Gertzman, Jay, 1985-1993 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Legman, Gershon, 1980-1993 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Pauline Roth's Death, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - "Personal Letters", 1976-1993 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - "Personal Letters", 1976-1993 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Plain Brown Correspondence," 1973-1993 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Publishers and Agents, 1982-1992 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Samuel Roth's Death, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Publishing 1919-1974
  This series contains a plethora of ads, mail order forms, promotional prototypes, and other ephemera including realia such as printing blocks and original artwork. Official documentation related to Roth's publishing business such as book contracts, receipts, and permissions to do business, along with sample stories from Roth's American Aphrodite: A Quarterly for the Fancy-Free can also be found here.
  - IV.1. Subseries: Promotional Materials, 1919-1960s
    Arranged alphabetically by book or magazine title when promoting a specific publication, or by slogan when promoting the press's products at large, this sub-series consists of materials used for promoting and advertising the books published by Roth's various imprints. The bulk of the materials are advertisement proofs, created during the years following World War II, but also included here are mail-order forms, negatives, photographs, and even printing blocks. There are a few clippings of book reviews, or receipts for ad payments, or ad drafts. Some of these proofs are oversized. As with previous series, folders created and arranged by Roth were kept intact and their original titles are in quotation marks. A few of the latter folders include correspondence and discarded advertising prototypes.
    - General
      - Designs and Lettering, 1950s (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Erotic Titles, Undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Order Forms and Promos, 1940s-1960s, Undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Various Titles--Promotions, Undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - "Ads," 1950s-1960s (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - American Aphrodite
      - General, 1950s-1960s (Box 39, Folder 9)